（帝国兵士）ハァ ハァ…
（帝国兵士）
うわあ！ 目が！
My eyes!
Medic! Someone get me a medic!
（帝国兵士）衛生兵！
衛生兵はいないか！
（帝国兵士）
ダメだ！
It's no good! The reinforcements are
just a random group of mages!
増援は寄せ集めの
魔導師しか…
（銃声）
A mage?
魔導師…
What are you doing, Visha?
（ハラルド）
何やってんだ ヴィーシャ！
（クルスト）
上空援護は もう無理だ！
We can't provide air support anymore!
小隊長殿の指示は？
What are the platoon commander's orders?
Sh-She cannot allow us to retreat.
（ヴィーシャ）
せ… 戦線後退は許容できない
We are to continue delaying
the enemy till the end.
徹底して遅滞戦闘に努めよと…
あっ！
（ヴィーシャ）キャッ！ うっ…
く… くうっ…
（ターニャ）聖徒よ―
Believers, have faith in the Lord's blessings.
主の恵みを信じよ
主は 我々をお見捨てにならず…
For the Lord will not abandon us.
Give me the power to destroy
the enemies of the Fatherland.
（ターニャ）我が祖国の敵を
討ち滅ぼす力を―
与えたまえ
An explosion spell...
爆炎術式…
If you have time for idle chatter,
（ターニャ）
無駄口をたたく暇があったら―
spend it doing all you can to survive.
生き残るために最善を尽くせ
小隊長殿
Platoon Commander?
We are soldiers.
我々は軍人だ
上が やれと言うのであれば
完遂するのみ
If the brass tells us to
do something, we do it.
（ヴィーシャ）
ターニャ･デグレチャフ少尉
Second Lieutenant Tanya Degurechaff.
Amidst the downpour of shells and bullets,
砲弾と銃弾の豪雨の中
気高く駆けるその姿は―
she flew high and nobly.
Like a fairy of the battlefield.
まるで戦場の妖精
（ターニャ）
戦火の絶えない呪われた世界で―
In a cursed world,
always engulfed in the flames of war,
there was a nation known as the Empire.
その国は“帝国”と呼ばれていた
“帝国 それは勝利である”
Its vast military and industrial power
made it virtually synonymous with victory.
…と豪語するに足る
絶大な国力と軍事力
It possessed a large number of
brilliant military minds and mages,
多数の魔導師と
俊英の参謀将校を擁する彼らは―
しかして 四方の列強全てが
仮想敵国であった
but it was surrounded on all sides
by strong potential enemies.
そのため 帝国軍は
内線戦略“プラン315”を策定
For this reason,
its military formulated Plan 315,
wherein border forces carried out
delaying actions in all theaters,
各方面軍をもって
遅滞戦闘に努めつつ―
buying time for a highly mobile,
concentrated main force to travel
中央本隊の集中的な機動運用により
敵を各個撃破せん―
to each area and defeat the enemy there.
At least, that was the plan.
…と するはずだった
Unified Year 1924, Imperial Capital Berun
Imperial Strategic Headquarters
What is the situation in the Rhine theater?
（ルーデルドルフ）
ライン戦線の状況は？
中央本隊の再配置は
どうなってる！
When will the main force be deployed there?
Vice Director of Strategy and Operations
Lieutenant Colonel Erich von Rerugen
Movement from the northern areas
is being delayed.
（レルゲン）
北方からの移動は
遅々として
進んでおりません
Deputy of Strategy and Operations
Brigadier General Kurt von Rudersdorf
We must adjust the rail and ship schedules,
船腹と鉄道ダイヤの
調整もあり―
so the deployment
will take another two weeks.
再配置には
２週間ほど必要かと
ふむ…
更なる戦線後退か
We must pull back the lines even more?
西方工業地帯も
危うくなるな
The western industrial areas
will be endangered.
増援を送ろうにも
We don't even have enough reserves
to send reinforcements.
本国は戦力予備すら
欠いております
We've been caught totally off-guard.
完全に隙を突かれたとしか…
そもそも 協商連合への
大規模攻勢が間違いだったのだ！
From the start, a major offensive against
the Entente Alliance was a mistake!
せめて
限定動員にとどめておけば…
If we'd kept ourselves to
a limited mobilization...
（ゼートゥーア）
共和国に動員の兆しなし…
We were the ones who failed to convince
the higher-ups that they were wrong
about the Republic's not mobilizing.
そう 判断した上官らを
翻意させられなかった我々のミスだ
Vice Director of Strategy and Operations
Brigadier General Hans von Zettour
Plan 315 is no longer viable.
（ゼートゥーア）
もはや プラン３１５は
機能していない
遅滞防御では
間に合わない以上
Since our attempts to delay
the enemy aren't working,
we'll have to move to a mobile defense, right?
機動防御戦へ
移行させるしかなかろう
But that will be difficult,
given the state of the Rhine theater.
ですが ライン戦線の現状では
困難です
消耗した現地部隊の限界を
超えているかと…
Our forces are depleted and exhausted,
so it's beyond their capacity.
We've already grabbed every
spare soldier we could send there.
（ゼートゥーア）既に
根こそぎ かき集めて―
予備戦力を用意した
That will buy some time.
時間稼ぎ程度には なるだろう
フン 持つべき者は優秀な同期
というわけか…
I suppose it helps to have
a talented contemporary, huh?
その発言は時期尚早だな
Isn't that statement premature?
何？
What?
（ゼートゥーア）報告によれば―
Reports say we've lost over half
the units we've deployed.
投入部隊は 既に半数がとけた
ライン戦線は
さながら地獄らしい
They say the Rhine theater
is now a living hell.
Imperial Army 205th Assault Mage Company Platoon 3 Commander
Second Lieutenant Tanya Degurechaff
地上２時方向 接敵
Enemies sighted on the ground, two o'clock.
Artillery spell.
砲撃術式 てーっ！
Fire!
は… はい！
Platoon 3 Member
Corporal Viktoriya Serebryakov
R-Right!
（共和国兵士）上空からだぞ！
（共和国兵士）魔導師のクソ野郎！
It's coming from above!
Damn the bastards!
（ハラルド）死ね！ 死ね！
Die! Die!
Platoon 3 Member
Corporal Harald von Vist
これでも食らいやがれ！
Take this...
You Republican bastards!
共和国のクソどもが！
Platoon 3 Member
Corporal Kurst von Walhorf
うっ… 砲兵隊だ
Artillery...
Take out the artillery.
砲兵隊をたたく！
（クルスト）来い ハラルド！
（ハラルド）了解！
Come with me, Harald!
Roger!
Both of you corporals, get back here.
両伍長(ごちょう) 直ちに戻れ！
我々の任務は
側面攻撃による遅滞戦闘だ！
Our mission is to delay the enemy
via flanking attacks.
Let us go, please.
（クルスト）行かせてください！
（ハラルド）今が好機なんです！
Now's our chance!
何が好機だ！ 戻れ！
Your chance to what?
Get back here!
これは命令だ！
This is an order!
Take this!
（クルスト）食らえ～！
All right!
（クルスト）よっしゃ～！
（ハラルド）
見ましたか？ 小隊長
Did you see that, Commander?
（クルスト）このまま
砲兵隊を潰してやる！
We'll keep going and crush the artillery!
う… うぷっ…
（ハラルド）
疲れて のども通らないな
Too tired to eat, huh?
Force it down if you have to.
無理にでも食え もたないぞ
You won't last otherwise.
（ヴィーシャ）二〇二中隊も
二〇三中隊も全滅したって…
They say the 202nd and 203rd Companies were wiped out.
I volunteered to come to the front lines.
志願して前線に来たのに
And now I've gotta work for that lieutenant?
あんな少尉の下に
就かされるとはな！
Platoon 3, of the 205th.
（通信士）二〇五第三小隊
小隊長殿がお呼びだ
Your captain is calling you.
We're being sent back home?
（クルスト）我々が 本国へ!?
I would say you're getting off lightly.
強制送還だけで済むのだ
ありがたいと思え
Be grateful.
The army has no need for officer candidates
who disobey orders.
我が軍に命令違反をする
士官候補生は必要ない
あ… あれは
砲兵隊をたたこうと！
But we were trying to take out the artillery!
You know how many of our infantry
they took out, don't you?
どれだけの歩兵がやられたか
ご存じでしょう！
言いたいことは それだけか？
Is that all you have to say?
An army is an organization.
軍隊とは組織
組織に必要なのは規則
And organizations are nothing without rules!
Dismissed.
以上だ
な… 納得できません！
I... I refuse to accept this!
I volunteered to come to the front lines!
小官は志願して
前線へ赴いたのです！
もとより 勝つか死ぬかの
選択肢しかありません！
My only choices are victory or death!
あ… 私も
クルスト伍長の意見に同意します
Me, too.
I agree with Corporal Kurst.
勇猛さこそが
帝国人の本分であります！
A man of the Empire is expected to be brave!
つまり 貴官らは
Then you're saying you'll disobey
your superior officer's orders again?!
再び 上官の命令に
逆らうというのだな！
少尉！
Lieutenant!
貴官らの意思は尊重しよう
I'll take your opinion under advisement.
But you'd best be prepared
to face some punishment.
だが ある程度の処罰は
覚悟しておけ
Corporal Serebryakov,
（シュワルコフ）
セレブリャコーフ伍長
Imperial Army 205th Assault Mage Company Commander
First Lieutenant Ihlen Schwarzkopf
is something wrong?
何か異変でも？
（ヴィーシャ）
シュ… シュワルコフ中尉！
Sch... Lieutenant Schwarzkopf!
Um, I don't see Corporal Kurst
or Corporal Harald.
あの… クルスト伍長と
ハラルド伍長が見えないもので…
That's right.
そうか お前は同期だったな
You were in their class, weren't you?
２人とも本日付で後方に転属だ
They've been transferred
to the rear as of today.
To the rear?
（ヴィーシャ）後方… ですか？
（シュワルコフ）ああ
Yeah.
They must be standing by in a pillbox now.
今頃はトーチカの中で
待機しているころだろう
This was at the suggestion of
Lieutenant Degurechaff.
転属はデグレチャフ少尉の
具申によるものだが
両伍長は少尉に
盾ついたらしいな
I heard they made her angry.
（ヴィーシャ）あ… はい
Y-Yes.
てっきり 厳しい処罰が下るのかと
思っていましたが…
I was sure they'd be harshly punished...
そっか 安全な後方に送るなんて…
I see.
They're being sent to the rear,
where it's safe.
（ヴィーシャ）
ハァ ハァ ハァ…
うっ… ハァ ハァ ハァ…
軍衣をまとった以上は
祖国に貢献をなせ
If you're wearing that uniform,
contribute to your country.
帝国には 無能な兵士を
養う余裕などない
The Empire doesn't have resources
to waste on weak soldiers.
R-Right.
は… はい
Corporal Serebryakov!
（ターニャ）
セレブリャコーフ伍長
はっ はい！
Yes?
Call an emergency meeting.
非常呼集だ
Bad news, everyone.
さて 中隊諸君
よろしくない知らせだ
Our 403rd Mage Company suddenly encountered
友軍の第四〇三魔導中隊が―
and entered combat with
two companies of enemy mages.
敵魔導２個中隊と
不意遭遇戦に突入
And they can't use artillery because
the observer mages were targeted,
砲兵で敵をたたこうにも
観測手の魔導師が狙われ―
弾着観測ができないそうだ
meaning they can no longer spot the shells.
敵の観測手狩りですか？
Enemy observer-hunters?
Oh, right.
そういえば
デグレチャフ少尉は
You've encountered them in the north,
Lieutenant Degurechaff.
以前 北方で
経験済みだったな？
And I never want to go through that again.
（ターニャ）
はい 二度とごめんですが
We will leave immediately
to rescue the observers.
我々は直ちに進発し
観測要員を救援する
Any questions?
何か質問は？
遅滞ならともかく
救援は難しいでしょう
We can perform a delaying action,
but rescuing them will be difficult.
（シュワルコフ）ほう…
その 九五式を持ってしてもか？
Even with that Type-95?
I can still fight,
but Corporal Serebryakov is at her limit.
（ターニャ）小官はともかく
セレブリャコーフ伍長は限界です
（ターニャ）救援に出たあげく―
I don't want to be the kind of incompetent
who goes to rescue someone,
部下と救助対象を死なせるような
無能には なりたくありません
only to lose them and her soldier.
（ヴィーシャ）
中隊長殿 志願します！
Company Commander, I volunteer for this!
I volunteer for the rescue mission!
私も救援任務に志願します！
Stop.
よせ 貴官には無理だ
You can't do it.
ぼ… 私とて帝国軍人です
I-I'm an Imperial soldier, too.
I'm certain I can complete the mission!
小官は任に堪えうると
確信します！
伍長！
Corporal!
Company Commander!
中隊長！
どうか どうか
行かせてください！
Please, please let me go!
You heard her, Second Lieutenant.
（シュワルコフ）だそうだ 少尉
I understand your concerns,
but she says she's all right.
配慮は分かるが
本人も こう言っているんだ
Roger.
了解しました
最善を尽くすところといたします
I'll do the best I can.
（ヴィーシャ）
あ… デグレチャフ少尉！
Lieutenant Degurechaff!
あ… ありがとうございます
Thank you.
Corporal,
（ターニャ）伍長
本当に覚悟は
できているのだな？
you're really ready for this, right?
はい！
Yes, ma'am.
Understood.
よろしい
では 仕事の時間だ
Time for work, then.
（ヴィーシャ）
はい！
Right!
Command Post, this is Bravo 01.
（帝国魔導師）コマンドポスト
こちらブラボー01
Enemy mages are stopping us
from artillery spotting!
（帝国魔導師）
現在 敵魔導師の攻撃により―
弾着観測ができない！
How much longer will reinforcements take?
増援は まだ来ないのか？
（帝国魔導師）くっ…
Command Post to Bravo 01.
（上官）
コマンドポストより ブラボー01へ
The 205th Mage Company is en route.
現在 二〇五魔導中隊が
向かっている
403rd Mage Company, continue spotting.
四〇三魔導中隊は
引き続き 観測を継続せよ
クソ！
Damn it!
Don't they understand what's going on?!
上は 状況を分かって
言っているのか!?
Republican Army 106th Recon Mage Company
Republican Army 106th Recon Mage Company Commander
First Lieutenant Augustin Hosman
（ホスマン）フン
I'd heard the Imperial mages were good.
帝国魔導師は優秀だと
聞いていたが―
Guess you can't trust rumors...
ウワサも信用できんなあ
Troops, find the remaining observers!
ショーン！ さっさと
残りの観測手を捜し出せ！
I've been trying, but they appear
to be hiding in the trenches.
（ショーン）
先ほどから試みていますが
どうやら 塹壕(ざんごう)に
隠れているようです
Then blow away anywhere
you think they might be.
だったら 怪しい区画ごと
吹き飛ばしてしまえ！
But a wide-area explosion spell
will drain our magic.
しかし 広域でも
爆裂術式ともなれば
魔力の消耗が…
It doesn't matter.
かまわん 最大火力だ
Maximum firepower.
"A-Attention, all units.
We've lost contact with friendly observers."
（通信兵）か… 各位に通達！
友軍観測手は“ロスト”
What a mess.
何たることだ…
Sh-Should we turn back?
（ヴィーシャ）
ひ… 引き返しますか？
いや 間に合わなかったのは
遺憾だが
No, it's a shame we weren't in time,
but we're inside enemy firing range.
既に敵の照射圏内
We've gotta earn our pay.
給料分の仕事は せねばなるまい
わ… 我々は単独小隊です
W-We only have one platoon.
We can't fight a whole company.
敵１個中隊を相手にするなど…
（ターニャ）“覚悟はできている”
そう言ったはずだが？
You said you were ready for this.
Our enemy is on an exhausting,
long-range mission.
（ターニャ）相手は消耗の激しい
長距離行軍中
And they've used a lot of firepower
to take out our observers.
その上 こちらの観測手狩りで
火力を消費している
There's a good chance we can win.
勝算は小さくない
But I guess losing new troops already
would hurt my promotion chances.
（ターニャ）とはいえ
新人を早々に失っては―
今後の昇進に響くか…
You are to rendezvous with
Lieutenant Schwarzkopf and provide support.
貴官らは シュワルコフ中尉と
合流して援護にあたれ
I'll go ahead and destroy three platoons.
私が先鋒(せんぽう)で３個小隊を潰す
The rest are yours.
残りは君たちのものだ
Man, it's rough being a salaryman.
まったく サラリーマンも
つらいものだな
S-Salary...?
サ… サラリー？
I pray unto God.
（ターニャ）我 神に祈らん
主よ 祖国を救いたまえ
Lord, save my Fatherland.
Magical signature, probably hostile,
approaching at high speed.
（共和国魔導師）
敵 増援とおぼしき
魔導反応が急速接近中
Visual confirmation on enemy target.
敵影 目視で確認
Distance, 2,000 meters.
距離 2,000… 1,800
1,800... 1,600...
1,600！ 速い！
She's fast!
フン 血迷ったか
They've gone mad, huh?
Prepare to intercept!
迎撃用意 てーっ！
Fire!
What are you doing?
何をやってる！
Unable to maintain flight spell!
Leaving the battlefield!
Scatter and climb!
各位散開！
上昇だ！ 限界まで昇れ～！
Get as high as you can!
（ターニャ）ハハッ！
（ショーン）隊長！
Commander!
Damn it.
（共和国魔導師）
チクショー！ ショーンの敵(かたき)だ！
Payback for Sean!
う… どこまで上昇する気だ？
How high up is she going?
（共和国魔導師）
隊長 限界高度です！
Commander, this is our max altitude.
（ホスマン）ええい… くっ！
Impossible.
バカな…
She's over 10,000 meters in the air.
高度１万を超えているぞ
（ターニャ）
んっ ハァ ハァ ハァ…
Attention.
告げる
You are trespassing on Imperial territory.
諸君らは
帝国の領域を侵犯している
An open comms channel?
オープン回線？
And this voice...
しかも この声…
やはり まだ子供か！
So she is just a kid?
This is our sky!
ここは我らが空 我らが故郷
Our home!
If you would stand against the Empire,
なんじらが祖国に不逞(ふてい)をなさば
容赦なく排除する
we shall eliminate you without mercy.
This is our task!
それが我らの使命
What an amazing patriot she is.
なんて 愛国心の強いお方だ
Answer me!
（ターニャ）答えよ！
Why do you invade the Empire,
our homeland?
帝国を 我らが祖国を
なぜ諸君らは侵さんと欲す？
If you want to play more,
遊び足りないのなら
鉛のオモチャをくれてやる！
I'll give you some lead toys!
Fire!
A decoy.
（共和国魔導師）デコイです！
（ターニャ）
ハァ… 交渉の余地もなしか
No room to negotiate, huh?
You bitch!
（ホスマン）
ふざけやがって！ うっ…
Spatial coordinates identified.
（ターニャ）空間座標 把握
Calculating stochastic evasion routes
for all targets.
各目標の乱数回避軌道 算出
Magical energy in chamber
within normal parameters.
チャンバーへの魔力充填(じゅうてん) 正常…
Attention, all allies. Prepare for impact.
友軍に告ぐ 衝撃に備えよ！
Oh, Lord... Save our Fatherland
from these faithless invaders.
主よ 信心なき輩(やから)に
祖国が侵されるのを救いたまえ
At the end of our long road,
はるか道の果て
我らは約束された地に至らん
we shall reach the promised land!
Detecting massive magical signature!
（共和国魔導師）強大な魔力反応！
Is she the devil?
悪魔か…!?
A diffusive magical explosion,
（シュワルコフ）
圧力限界に達した魔力が―
caused when magic under maximum pressure
mixes with the surrounding air.
空気と混合されて起こる
拡散魔力爆発だ
Even if you dodge the impact,
衝撃を回避しても―
you can't escape the oxygen deprivation
or carbon monoxide poisoning that follows.
燃焼による酸欠と
一酸化炭素中毒は避けられまい
We didn't need to provide any support.
援護の必要などなかったな…
In this cruel world of wars,
過酷な戦争の世で―
there's no mage you can count on like her.
あれほど頼りになる
魔導士官も いまい
The battle is over.
既に勝敗は決した
Surrender now, and we'll guarantee
your rights as prisoners
投降するならば―
ヴォルムス陸戦条約により
捕虜としての権利を保障する
under the Treaty of Worms.
ハァ…
Republican Capital Parisée
Ministry of Defense
This is the record of a computation jewel,
（ビアント）
これは―
とある戦闘後に
回収された―
Republic Army 2nd Mage Company
Lieutenant Colonel Severin Bientot
which was recovered after a certain battle.
演算宝珠の記録です
This single mage wiped out the 106th Company.
このような魔導師１人に―
あの 一〇六中隊が
壊滅させられたそうです
Her appearance was first
confirmed two months ago.
当該魔導師の出現が
確認されたのは２か月前
She's a named mage
whose background is unclear,
詳細は不明の
ネームドですが―
but our soldiers call her...
自軍における二つ名は…
"The Devil of the Rhine"?
（ド･ルーゴ）
“ラインの悪魔”か…
Redeployment of our central forces
to the Rhine has been completed.
（レルゲン）
ライン戦線への―
中央本隊の再配置は―
無事に完了したそうです
So we somehow made it in time.
（ルーデルドルフ）
どうにか間に合ったか
We put pretty heavy demands on you, huh?
戦務には随分
無理をさせたな
Don't worry about it.
（ゼートゥーア）
気にするな
It's all for our country's sake.
全ては我が国のためだ
I must thank you somehow.
（ルーデルドルフ）
そうはいかん
How about one of my best bottles of wine?
この借りは
秘蔵のワインでどうだ？
（ゼートゥーア）
フッ… あいにく―
I'm afraid I've put off drinking
until our victory.
酒は勝利の時まで
控えている
フッ… 堅物め
Stubborn...
（テーブルを
たたく音）
Lieutenant Colonel Rerugen,
（ルーデルドルフ）レルゲン中佐
何か気になることでも？
is something wrong?
No, it's just...
いえ ただ…
Just what?
（ルーデルドルフ）
“ただ”何だ？
W-Well, this report says
あ… はい
この報告書によれば
ライン戦線には
that Second Lieutenant Tanya Degurechaff
was sent to the Rhine theater.
ターニャ･デグレチャフ少尉が
配属されていると…
Kurst and Harald are dead?
（ヴィーシャ）クルストと
ハラルドが戦死？
While they were on standby,
an enemy shell struck their pillbox.
（シュワルコフ）
待機中のトーチカに―
敵の砲弾が直撃したらしい
It's a shame.
残念だな
No.
そんな…
Does the platoon commander know?
小隊長殿は このことを？
No, probably not yet.
（シュワルコフ）いや まだだろう
The one called "White Silver"?
（ルーデルドルフ）
“白銀(はくぎん)”の二つ名
The one who was awarded
the Silver Wings Assault Badge?
銀翼突撃章の叙勲者か
It's surprising to see an ace at her age.
この若さでエースとは 驚きだな
What about her?
その少尉が何か？
I once had the opportunity to
see Lieutenant Degurechaff.
実は 小官は以前
デグレチャフ少尉を
見かける機会がありました
Excuse me.
（ヴィーシャ）失礼します
小隊長殿に報告したいことが…
There's something I want to report.
What is it?
（ターニャ）何だ？
Corporals Kurst and Harald—
（ヴィーシャ）実は
クルスト伍長とハラルド伍長が…
（ターニャ）死んだのか？
They're dead?
Wh-Where did you learn that?
ど… どこでそれを!?
It's self-evident.
（ターニャ）
聞かなくとも自明だろう
A pillbox doesn't move.
It's an ideal target for artillery.
動かないトーチカなど
砲兵にとって格好の的
A perfect place for men who wanted to die.
死にたがっていたヤツらには
ちょうどよい
If I may be so forward as
to give you my opinion.
その時の印象を
せん越ながら申し上げますと…
You didn't know this would happen, did you?
まさか 小隊長殿は
こうなることを承知で…
（レルゲン）あれは…
She is...
a monster in the form of a little girl!
（レルゲン）
幼女の皮をかぶった化物です！
This program is fiction.
All persons, groups, places, laws,
and names appearing in it have
no relation to the real world.
Episode One
The Devil of the Rhine